

EMBEDDED SOFTWARE ENGINEER

473 West Happfield Drive, Arlington Heights, IL

□ 682-241-8753 |

□ knguyen2133@qmail.com | □ knguyen2133 | □ knguyen2133

Professional Summary

Embedded Software Engineer with five years of professional experience in interest of dealing with embedded systems in IoT, automotive, and aerospace. Proficiency in developing software on the driver level. Ample experience exercising the full software development life-cycle which includes leading teams during integration and testing along with prominent communication skills and constructive attitude.

Experience

Northrop Grumman Rolling Meadows, Illinois

EMBEDDED SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Nov. 2019 - Present

- Integrate kernel modules communication over multiple SBCs and sensors (I²C, PCIE)
- · Develop camera tracking software
- Work with cross compilation between architectures for development (ARM, x86_64)
- Setup networks and embedded Linux environments (RedHat, Yocto)
- · Assisted multiple departments in documentation, design, and testing
- Managed version control and agile development (Atlassian)
- Coded mainly in C++ and C

L&T Technology Services Limited

Peoria, Illinois

May 2018 - Nov 2019

EMBEDDED SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- · Contracted to multiple companies for Development and Verification: Collins Aerospace, John Deere
- Manage requirements under DO-178C standards
- Produce/Modify test scripts for CAN Protocol verification (Python, Bash, C)
- Facilitate version control (Mercurial)
- Document reports for changes in DOORS requirements and source code

Ayoka Systems Arlington, Texas

EMBEDDED/WEB DEVELOPER

Jul. 2017 - May 2018

- Develop software for microcontrollers that require RTOS features
- Worked in embedded Linux environment (Debian)
- Assist in communication between microcontrollers and upload to Amazon S3 (RF, UART, SPI, I²C, Wifi)
- Experience Validation/Verification process with clients
- Initially intern for six months experiencing

Analyze projects for technical faults

Unit Testing

Manage repositories (Github)

Skills

Programming C++, C, Python, Bash, Git, Java

Operating Systems RedHat, Yocto, Debian
Comm Protocols I²C, PCIE, SPI, UART, BLE, RF
Microcontrollers Raspberry Pi, Arduino, TI

Processors ARM, x86_64, TI

Languages English

Education _

University of Texas at Arlington

Arlington, Texas

Aug. 2014 - May 2018

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Extracurricular Activities _

Software Capstone Project

University of Texas at Arlington

- · Assemble a smart shoe that displays images on an E-ink screen via BLE using a nRF52 chip that was sponsored under Bioworld
- Required agile development

Personal Projects

- Designed an alarm system that triggers based on motion and temperature
- Built a TRISC that read instructions on RAM
- · Programmed TI microcontrollers to transfer temperature, ambient, and humidity data through RF communication

JANUARY 22, 2022 KEVIN NGUYEN · RÉSUMÉ